Do you know that there is a
protection gap of 87% people in India, there
is an insurance gap. Suppose a family
needs insurance of Rs., then
they have insurance of only Rs. This is the
main reason for the insurance gap.
Very few people have purchased term insurance.
Most of the people have purchased traditional and savings plans.
Now people are slowly becoming aware and
they are also purchasing term policies,
but there are many people who are
still not able to purchase term policies.
For example, the backbone of India is the
self-employed people, the
traders, the businessmen, the small
entrepreneurs who are
earning money by setting up their own business,
but they are not able to buy a term policy. The reason is that
when a person goes to buy a term policy, there are
many terms and conditions in the term plan.
First, you will get a term plan only if you are a graduate, otherwise you will
not get it. Second, you will get a term plan only if
your income in your Income Tax Return (ITR) is Rs. 5
lakh or more,
otherwise you will not get it.  Many
times, due to education, customers are
unable to purchase a policy, or sometimes
due to income tax (ITR) issues, they are unable to purchase a term policy.
Keeping this in mind, Bajaj India Life
Insurance has launched a new term plan,
iSecure. Under this plan, those with low
education and low income can also purchase this policy.
Even if you have
passed 10th standard, you can still purchase this plan. Even if
your income is only Rs 8 lakh, you
can still purchase this policy. And if you do
not have ITR but have surrogate income, such as an
FD in your name, investments in mutual funds, a
car with an
ID of more than Rs 4 lakh, or
other investment tools, which I will
explain in detail later, you will still be
able to purchase this policy. Even if you
want an insurance cover of Rs 25 lakh, you will still be
able to purchase this policy. The Rs 25 lakh term
plan is available with very few companies in the industry
because many times customers invest Rs
50 lakh or Rs 1 crore.  Those who are not able to take a term plan,
they find the premium high and
want to take a little less insurance cover at a little cheaper. So most of the companies say that
our term plan starts from 50 lakhs.
You will be able to purchase this term plan from 25 lakhs as well.
Let's understand the features of this product and
watch the full video.
Thank you. If you liked the video, then my
self-employed. Its
feature is because
self-employed people are getting this term plan on an income of 1 lakh.
Till now, salaried people are getting
term plans on 1 lakh and other companies also provide term plans
but self-employed people are
not getting term plans on an income of 1 lakh to 1 lakh. So
this plan is for those who
are businessmen, small entrepreneurs whose income in ITR is
less. This term plan is
very good for those people. Secondly, here you can purchase insurance
between 25 lakhs to 1 crore.
You can buy insurance up to 25 lakhs,
40 lakhs, 35 lakhs, 50 lakhs, 70 lakhs, 75 lakhs or 1 crore.  If
you also want to take insurance cover, then
you will be able to take it. Along with this,
this policy will cover you till the age of 85.
You can take a policy term till the age of 85. If
you want to keep it 70 or 60, you can
keep it, but
you will get this protection till the maximum age of 85 years. Along with
this, many premium payment
options have been given, here you
can pay the premium every year, you
can pay the premium in monthly mode, if you want to pay the premium in a short time, that is, you
want to complete the policy by paying the premium in 5 years,
then also there are premium payment options for 5 years, 10 years, 15 years, 20 years,
25 years.
Along with this, its underwriting
is quite good because here you can get this
policy even with less education and income. This policy
gives you 360 degree protection cover.
Here you are also getting riders.
You can take a rider for accidental death benefit.
You can add a rider for permanent or partial disabilities
and your insurance cover will be one.  You can balance it well so that you get
insurance cover in case of natural death as well.
In case of accidental death, suppose you take
insurance cover of Rs. 1 crore plus Rs. 1 crore and the
family gets Rs. 2 crore. Many times, there is
no death in an accident but the person becomes disabled, a person becomes
handicapped, then
you will get that benefit in this rider as well. Along with this, you
can also purchase this policy under the MWPA Married Women Property Act. Businessmen who mostly
run their business through loans, suppose they have taken a
loan and now if they die, then
who will
repay the loan or if they have taken a normal policy, then
whatever loan money comes, the creditor will take it
back, your wife and children will
not get anything. But this policy is
taken under the MWPA Act, so
only your wife and children will have the right over the money that comes in case of your death, no
one else will have any right over it.
Apart from this, you will also be able to purchase this policy for surrogate income. If
you
want to take insurance cover up to Rs. 1 crore, then also you will be
able to take it. Regarding the eligibility criteria of this plan,
this policy
Any person between 18 years to 65 years
can purchase this policy, who is at least 10th
pass, his income should be 8 lakh or more.
Talking about the minimum sum insured,
you can take a minimum insurance cover of 25 lakhs, maximum up to
1 crore only. Here you will get
insurance cover of more than 1 crore,
if you want to take cover, you will not get it.
You can also take insurance cover up to 1 crore in this.
Talking about the premium
payment term in the policy, here regular pay, 5 pay,
10 pay, 15, 20, 25 are given. Talking about the policy term,
suppose you have to
increase the premium for 5 years, then the minimum policy term will
be 10, otherwise you can do your age and policy as 85
minus your age. Suppose your
age is 35 years, then 85 minus 35, 50 years, so
you can select any policy term from 10 years to 50 years, 11
years, 12 years, 15 years  If
you want to take a policy term of 25 years, 35 years, 45 years or 50 years, then
you can take it. If the premium
payment term is 10 years, then the minimum policy
term will be 11. Otherwise, using the same formula,
you will be able to take a policy term like 85 minus your age. Let us consider the
benefit illustration of Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance's iSecure best term plan. A
customer named Anil Rajput,
whose
FFFS is 2
and his age is 35 years, is purchasing Bajaj Life's Bajaj
Life iSecure policy,
which is a non-linked, non-participating plan,
meaning it neither participates in bonus
nor is it a unit-linked policy or term insurance
policy. Here, he is taking a policy term of 40 years, which
means his insurance cover will remain till the age of 75. If
he decides to increase the premium for 15 years, then
GST on this plan is at 18.
Modi 3.0, the new government has come. It is expected that
GST on term plans would have been very high at 18
and will be reduced in the future.  More and
more Indians will be able to afford it and
more and more Indian families will be protected
by term life insurance. The
new government should definitely
modify the GST on 18% a little. 5-6% is
enough for term plans, but on 18% it becomes too much. Let's
assume that the customer is
taking an insurance cover of 25 lakhs. If you
go into the industry, you will find very few plans
where you get an insurance cover of 25 lakhs.
Suppose the customer
wants to pay the premium in monthly mode, by
paying a monthly premium of just ₹1.25,
he can take insurance of 25 lakhs and
protect his family.
Even in this 1500, if you notice, only 92%
goes into Bajaj Live and the rest is
taken by the government. Due to GST on 18% it becomes 1525.
So now let's see that your annual premium will be
15510 V plus GST and from day one your
insurance cover will be 2 lakh rupees and
this insurance cover will remain for 40 years.
For how many years did you pay the premium? Only for 15
years, after that you do not have to pay,
despite that your insurance cover of Rs 25 lakh will
continue. There is one more thing in this plan
that the surrender value will be given whichever is higher among the two, Guaranteed
Surrender Value and Special Surrender Value.
But when will the surrender value be generated? When the
premium payment term is completed, not
from the second year. So you can also notice this. So
what is higher among these two,
let's see, you get the surrender value of Rs 4526.
Now let's see the second option. Let's
see an example. In the second example, the
same customer is 35 years old, he is
taking a cover for 40 years only. He is paying the premium for 15 years only.
This time he is purchasing an insurance cover of Rs 50 lakh.
Okay, so now the
premium that was coming here was Rs 00, if you notice it earlier,
it should have been Rs 1525, but
here you
got a slightly cheaper amount due to taking more insurance.  I got 2593,
though only 297 goes to Bajaj, the rest is
Government 3.0, I hope they will reduce it in the future,
I am repeating it again and again
because term plan is a necessity for every family,
every family should buy it and GST on this is 18% this time,
this time I hope that
they will reduce it in the third term or they hope to reduce it in the budget that is going to come
in a month, so if you
pay 000 rupees premium for 15 years, then you will get an
insurance cover of 50 lakhs for the next 40 years
and you can also see the surrender value here,
if the customer wants to surrender, then
he can also surrender in the future,
now suppose the customer's income is a little
higher and he can also afford to
pay the premium and he wants high security,
so this time he decided that he is
purchasing term insurance of ₹ 1 crore,
then he will get an insurance cover of
7774 rupees in 1 month, along with GST he will have to
pay 4453 rupees for 15 years
and his 1 crore  You will get insurance cover of Rs. 10000 for the
next 40 years till 75. Now the
good thing for you people is that even if you are a 2nd pass,
you can take this plan. Your
income is Rs. 8 lakh. Suppose you are
taking an insurance cover of Rs. 50 lakh. If the customer is 35 years old, then
he gets 25 times the insurance cover.
So 25 times of Rs. 1 lakh becomes 62 lakh something
insurance. Suppose you are
taking a cover of Rs. 50 lakh. Even a 10th pass is getting it. It is
also available on an income of Rs. 8 lakh. And if
you do not have IT, then
you can purchase this policy from surrogate income also. So this is an
excellent product. If you are not able to take term
insurance due to any education or income,
then this
is the best product for you. Contact today to purchase
9094 3412. Thank
you. Now let us see with the premium affordability. There are
three persons. One person is
35 years old, one is 40 years old and one is 45 years old. All
three persons have their own insurance cover.  He
wants to take it till the age of 70, that is, the first person
whose age is 35 years is taking a policy term of 35 years, the
second person is
taking a policy term of 30 years, the third person is
taking a policy term of 25 years. The first
person is a garment shop owner
and his monthly income is only ₹2500000, hence
he is taking an insurance cover of ₹50 lakh. The second person is a grocery shop owner, his monthly income is ₹0000, so he is
taking an insurance cover of ₹50 lakh and the third
person is a jewellery shop owner, his
monthly income is ₹1 lakh and he is
taking an insurance cover of ₹1 lakh. So the first
person whose income is ₹225000 is
taking an insurance cover of ₹25 lakh. Suppose he
pays a premium for ₹25 lakh in monthly mode,
then by
paying a premium of ₹6656 plus GST, he
can get an insurance cover of ₹25 lakh till the
age of 70,
if he pays the premium for 15 years and the
policy runs till the age of 70.  In monthly mode,
his premium will be ₹1075 and if he
pays premium for 10 years, then it will be ₹1443.
You can also see the premium in monthly mode. A
40-year-old person who is
taking an insurance cover of ₹50 lakh
can pay regular premium for ₹1532. He
can take the policy by paying 15-year premium for ₹1 and can
also take this policy by paying 10-year premium for ₹3194. A person who is
taking an insurance cover of ₹1 crore has a policy term of 25 years. If the
customer is 45 years old, then
he can take a regular premium work policy for ₹3434. He
can also take a policy of ₹1 crore by paying 15-year premium and the premium for 10 years is only ₹
549 and he will be able to take an insurance cover of ₹1 crore. So,
according to different needs,
according to different income profiles, according to different premium
payment terms, you
can give the premium chart here which is quite easy and
affordable. Less education and less income.
For income profile,
salaried people can also take this policy for self-employed people.
If you want to take it, then surrogate people
can also take this policy because
in India, many 10th pass people also work on salary,
they will also be
able to take it. Now, if you do not have income proof
but you have surrogate income,
you will be able to take this term policy even after giving the document of surrogate income.
What will be included in surrogate income? Suppose
you have an FD of ₹ lakh in your name or you have a statement of up
to 8 lakh invested in mutual funds
or you are
doing SIP, systematic investment in mutual funds
and
you are doing SIP of 000 per month or
you have a car which is in your name
and whose ID is also insured declared
value of 4 lakh, even then you will be
able to purchase the policy by giving this document, if you are
paying home loan EMI etc. of
000 or more per month then also
You will also be able to buy this policy through its statement.
If you use a credit card and
your credit limit is even ₹ lakh in the credit card,
then also you will be able to purchase this policy through the
statement of the credit card
and if you have a bank
statement where your average monthly
balance is 67000, then by giving this statement or any
one of these documents,
you can purchase this term policy of 25 lakh to 1 crore.
Two riders are given in this policy of surrogate income,
rider of accidental death benefit. If you want to
add a rider of accidental cover along with natural cover, then
you can do it and if you also want to add a rider of
accidental
disabilities, partial and permanent
disabilities, then you can do it.
If you
take a normal policy without a rider, even if there is a
death in an accident, then you will
get a claim but if you add an accidental rider, then
suppose normal cover of 1 crore and
accidental cover of 1 crore, then death in an accident  If it
happens, you get two crores. If you do
not take the rider, in case of death due to any reason, accident
or natural death, and you have
taken a policy of one crore, then you definitely get one crore.
Loan is not available in the policy of other benefits and features.
Talking about tax benefits,
you will get tax benefit up
to ₹ 1 lakh under the Income Tax Section ATC and the death benefit is tax
free. Talking about the grace period,
you will also get a grace period of
30 days in the policy. If due to any reason you are
not able to pay the premium on time,
you will get a grace period for one month. During that time, your
insurance will also start and you
can pay the premium. After this, if you do not
pay the premium, the policy will lapse.
You have also been given a free look period which is of 15 days.
However, according to the new norms of IRD, if it has become
30 days, then you will get a free look
period of 15 to 30 days.
Surrender benefit: It is important to remember here
that there is a surrender benefit but it will be available
after the premium payment term, from the second or
third year.  You will not get it.
You will get it only after the premium payment term that you have kept.
But if you are paying regular premium
then surrender benefit
is not available. Talking about revival period,
if for some reason you are not able to pay the premium for
one year, two years, three years, then you can
come back for medical test by paying late fees etc. The
company can also ask for the medical report
and you will get 5 years time. You can continue the
policy again by paying the entire premium etc.
If I were to summarise it, then this is an
excellent product. The
plan is keeping in mind the self-employed, low-income and less educated people. Excellent options for surrogate income have been
given. 25 lakh, 50 lakh, 1 crore, whatever is the
insurance cover according to your need,
that benefit has been given.
Many good options have been given for premium payment. If
you want to take this policy in monthly mode also,
you can take it. So, keeping
in mind your various needs, 360 degree is
a good and excellent product.
Very few companies in the industry have such a
plan which is for 10th pass.  We give self-employed
people the opportunity to purchase a pure term policy. So,
if you too have
not yet fulfilled your insurance gap, if you
need insurance of ₹1 for your family,
you also have insurance of ₹1, then purchase
term insurance for yourself and your family today itself
and
also tell your friends who have low education and income,
who tried the term plan but could
not get it, tell them that there is
such a plan in the industry right now which you can also get.
If you want to purchase a policy from me, then tell
me
on WhatsApp2. If you liked the video, then on leaving you will
get more than youtube3 videos related to insurance which will
help you in your financial planning. Thank you so much,
Jai Hind.